### Philip Taylor

Flat 24, Town Centre House, Southam Road, Banbury, OX16 2BZ Mobile: 07426 397240 Email: ptaylor@taylorworld.one

**Personal Profile:** I am able to demonstrate with over eighteen years' experience in an IT environment and customer facing roles, extensive and broad IT knowledge and customer service skills and a high willingness to learn. My work experience demonstrates a consistently high level of punctuality, good communication skills as well as being a good team worker. I always work to ensure that tasks are completed on time and to a consistently high standard.

## **Key Skills:**

- IT: I have extensive IT skills with a variety of software and hardware knowledge. I have successfully completed IT training courses and I support others to effectively use technology
- Own initiative: I am able to work using my own initiative, effectively and efficiently working independently, planning my tasks for the day, under limited constraints, especially during busy periods as demonstrated in my previous retail roles especially with The Entertainer
- Team work: I am able to effectively and efficiently work in groups and support others, as demonstrated in all my previous work experience
- Languages: I have fluent German language skills, both written and verbal, after living in Germany for 11 years

### Work History:

# 10th September 2019 - Present: Activate Learning, Learning Environments Support: Responsibilities include:

- Organisation of books and learning materials within the library
- Supporting students in the use of resources like the computers, printers and books
- Maintaining a calm and quiet environment, in order to ensure students maximise productivity

# 15th - 23rd December 2018: Sainsburys/Adecco, Replenishment:

Responsibilities include:

- Replenishment of stock on the shop floor, while maintaining health and safety standards and doing correct date rotation on stock, and correct timed handling of frozen and chilled foods
- Management of stock in the warehouse, which includes returning unreplenished stock back into the warehouse

## July 2018: Marks and Spencer's, Work experience:

Responsibilities include:

- In the food hall the main responsibilities included, bringing out new stock from the warehouse, maintaining standards on the shop floor, refreshing stock in the various sections on the shop floor, and date rotation of foods.
- In the men's clothing department the responsibilities included, maintaining standards on the shop floor, bringing out new stock for the shop floor and organizing it into the various sections and maintaining standards on the shop floor

## 2008 - Present: User Support Engineering:

Responsibilities include:

- Supporting in my free time as a volunteer, users on both forums, irc and mailing lists who have problems and need support with Ubuntu, Debian, OpenBSD and Android, and other related technologies, which include SQL, postgresql and LaTeX/tex.
- Accurate and professional communication, typing and word processing skills. A broad range of knowledge and experience in a variety of different areas and able to demonstrate good problem solving skills

# Jan 2017 - May 2017: The Entertainer: Sales Assistant

Responsibilities included:

• Safely and efficiently sorting incoming stock into sections within the stock room in a timely and organised manner

- Keeping the shop floor and stock room tidy to ensure a high level of cleanliness
- Serving customers and assisting customers on the shop floor, providing a high level of customer care
- Demonstrating new toys to customers, while ensuring a high level of health and safety, to maximise sales

## Aug 2016 - Dec 2016: Scope: Volunteer Retail Assistant

Responsibilities included:

• Efficiently serving customers on the till, preparing and tagging stock accurately, and taking stock onto the shop floor while maintaining merchandising standards

## Dec 2015: Shaw Trust: Volunteer Retail Assistant

Responsibilities as above.

## Jul 2014 - February 2015: Blue Cross: Volunteer Retail Assistant

Responsibilities as above.

# 2003 - 2004: BTech: Systems Support and Maintenance Engineer

Responsibilities included:

- Maintenance of staff computers as well as company servers to a high standard and in timely manner
- Installing new networking hardware and software and diagnosing network problems as they occur in a quick and efficient manner
- Troubleshooting desktop, server, software and network problems to set procedures, and fixing them while minimising interruption and downtime

# **Education and Training:**

- Mar 2018: Activate Learning, Banbury and Bicester College
  - Digital Literacy
- Jan 2018: E-Careers
  - Level 3 Customer service diploma
  - Apple and Android App developer package
  - Basic accounting
- Oct 2017: Activate Learning, Banbury and Bicester College
  - Level 1 Award in Personal Progression
  - food retail and customer service course
  - Waitrose Sector Based Work Academy
- 2004: Sheffield College
  - CISCO IT Essentials 1 OCR Level 2
- $\bullet\,$  2000 2002: Dewsbury College
  - GNVQ Advanced ICT, A 'Level

Educated in Germany for eleven years and achieved qualifications equivalent to 5 GCSE passes in various subjects.

**Interests:** I am interested in physics and the sciences generally, the skills involved are both creative and imaginative, being a logical thinker and thinking out of the box and good mathematics skills.

# References are available upon request.